Birthday
Hey, hey!
（相生祐子(あいおいゆうこ)）ねえ ねえ
（長野原(ながのはら)みお）うん？
Let's throw Nano-chan a birthday party!
（祐子）
なのちゃんの
誕生日会をしよう
（みお）
おお いいね　いつなの？
Sounds good.
When should we do it?
Today.
（祐子）今日
（みお）本日？
Today?!
You have to tell me these things earlier!
ちょ そういうのは
事前に教えてくれなきゃ
Sorry.
ごめーん
Well...
ええ  うーん
どうしよう
What should we do?
We haven't prepared anything...
何も用意してないよ
Well, it's not like today is her birthday.
まあ 今日が―
なのちゃんの誕生日ってわけでも
ないんだけどね
You didn't ask?!
（みお）聞いてないの？
Exactly.
（祐子）そゆこと
（みお）どゆこと？
What?!
サプライズってこと
It's going to be a surprise!
What?!
どゆこと？
Let's also...
（水上麻衣(みなかみまい)）はかせの…
（祐子･みお）あっ
Let's also throw a birthday party for the professor.
はかせの誕生日も
一緒にしよう
Good idea!
おお いいね
一石二鳥じゃん
Two birds with one stone!
Let's do this!
やろう やろう
Well, I guess a happy surprise is fun for both sides.
（みお）まあ でも
うれしいサプライズは
やるほうも やられるほうも
楽しいもんね
All right.
よし！ 分かった
On our way home, let's buy some cake!
じゃあ 帰りに みんなで
ケーキでも買っていこうか
All right!
よっしゃ！ 麻衣ちゃんも
それでオーケー？
Are you okay with that, Mai-chan?
I forgot my wallet.
がま口忘れた
（祐子）どーん！
（みお）どーん！
T-That's too bad.
し… しかたない
じゃあ ゆっこと私で
Well then, Yukko and I will...
I also forgot my wallet!
私も財布 忘れちゃった
（みお）どーん！
I'm begging you, Mio-chan!
みおちゃん お願い！
Well, I never paid you back the money I lost at the amusement park,
前に遊園地で落としたお金も
返してなかったし―
so I guess I'll pay for today.
とりあえず 今日は
私が出しておくよ
Well, I'll go tell Nano-chan we're having a birthday party!
じゃあ なのちゃんに
誕生日会やるって言ってくる
What happened to the surprise?!
サプライズどこいったの？
Geez.
まったく ゆっこはバカだな
Yukko, you're an idiot.
Wha...
さ… 笹原(ささはら)先輩にフラれたくせに
Yet you got dumped by Sasahara-senpai...
わーお
フ… フラれてないよ
I wasn't dumped!
You ran away crying.
泣きながら逃げてったくせに
あっ あれは…
That was...
Just because they were holding hands...
…てか
腕組んでただけで―
...doesn't mean they were going out!
つきあってるか
どうかなんて―
分かんないでしょ
I never actually asked him about it,
まだ本人にも
確かめたわけじゃないし
so it's not like I got dumped or anything!
だから全然
フラれたわけじゃないし
It's not like I gave up!
だから 全然
あきらめたとかでもないし
I still like him!
まだ 全然好きだし！
Let's leave it at that!
そこんとこ よろしくっ！
Shinonome Institute
All right!
（東雲(しののめ)なの）
よし！ 忘れ物なしっと
Nothing forgotten...
Nichijou 110
Professor, I'm heading out now!
はかせ
それじゃあ いってきまーす
Nano!
（はかせ）なの
（なの）お？
（はかせ）すっぽん！
どどど… どうしたんですか？
はかせ
What's with you, Professor?
I made a small one, so I'm taking this one off.
今ね 小(ち)っちゃいやつ
作ったから 取るね
Professor, what do you mean by "a small one"?
はかせ 小っちゃいやつって
何ですか？
By small... uh...
（はかせ）
小っちゃいやつはね えっとね
Will that make my back smooth?
それって 背中つるつるに
なるんですか？
おっ なるけど
It will.
But even on top of the small one...
でも 小っちゃいのの その上から…
あれ？ おお おおっ？
えっと あれ？
（はかせ）なの
（なの）はいっ
Nano.
Yes!
なくなっちゃった
I lost it.
なの！ 大丈夫なの？
Nano!
Are you okay?
Why are you guys yelling in the morning?
（阪本(さかもと)）
朝から何やってんだ 騒がしい
It's so loud...
ドワッハア！
Kid, why did you set up a trap?!
ガキ！ てめえ なんてトラップ
仕掛けてやがんだ
ああ！ 阪本が
小っちゃいやつ壊した
Sakamoto broke the small thing!
W-What? No!
（阪本）えっ？ ああ… いや 違う
Well...
（阪本）
いやっ ううっ その…
Sakamoto made Nano cry.
あー！ 阪本 なの 泣かした
No way!
It's your fault for leaving it on the ground!
お前が床に置いてんのが
悪いんだろ！
I'm heading off to school.
（なの）学校いってきます
（はかせ）
えっ？ えっと うーん
Nano...
なの　忘れ物
You forgot this.
Nano...
なの？
I'll make another one real quick.
また すぐ作れるけど
Will it be made before I get back?
帰ってくるまでに
出来てますか？
Well, I can make it really quick.
だって すぐ作れるから
ぱあ　はかせっ
Professor!
学校いってきます
I'm heading off to school!
All right!
（阪本）ううう
（なの）いってきまーす
I'm going!
Shinonome Institute
Have a safe trip!
（はかせ）いってらっしゃーい
（阪本）
い… いってらっしゃーい
Have a safe trip...
（校長先生）ハア ハア ハア
Principal
Well, that's odd...
Principal & Vice Principal
（教頭先生）
あれ？ おかしいですね
（校長）教頭
Vice Principal...
This statue is from when I was the principal...
（教頭）これは 以前―
私が校長の玉座にいたときの
銅像ですね
That's odd.
おかしいなあ
ここには 東雲校長の像がないと
おかしいのに
Where's the statue of you, Principal Shinonome?
ハア ハア ハア
Geez.
まったく 近頃の若者のいたずらは
ユーモアがあるというか―
Kids these days with their sophisticated pranks...
ちゃめっ気があるというか
Or is it something else?
（教頭）それともなんですか？
（校長）ハアッ
Could I possibly have an admirer?
（教頭）
私の支持者でもいるんですかね
ハッハッハッ
Mister Vice Principal!
（配送業者）
教頭先生　運び終わりました
We've finished moving it!
The statue is fine here, correct?
（配送業者）この像は
ここでよかったんですよね？
（教頭）
ああ… いや あっ いや
I didn't say anything...
私は何も…
（校長）ハア ハア ハア
Vice Principal, this is...
教頭 これは？
（教頭･校長）ハア ハア
（教頭）ま… まったく
最近の若者のいたずらは―
Well, the pranks these youngsters do...
何というか
手が込んでいるというか
They're well plotted out.
す… すいません
この像も持っていってください
Sorry, can you take this statue as well?
えっ？ この ちゃっちいほう
片づけちゃうんですか？
You want to take away this cheap statue, too?
Cheap...
（教頭）ちゃっち？
Got it!
分っかりました
I'll take away this pathetic one as well!
じゃあ このダッサいほうも
持ってっちゃいますね
Pathetic...
（教頭）ダッサ
We're taking this stupid one, too!
おーい　このショッパイほうも
持っていくってさ
Now, now, Vice Principal, don't be so gloomy.
（校長）まあまあ 教頭先生
お気になさらずに
Well, we're taking it with the stinky one!
じゃあ さっきのクッサイほうと
一緒に持ってっちゃいますね
What?!
（校長）なんと！
Go Soccer Club 8
（大工健三郎(だいくけんざぶろう)）あれ？ 鍵開いてる
Huh?
It's unlocked.
（関口(せきぐち)ユリア）ああ
Oh, you were here, Sekiguchi?
なーんだ 関口いたのか
I wanted to be first,
一番に来ようと思って―
so I even went through the effort of flying a Blackbird here.
ブラックバード
すっ飛ばしてきたのに
What is it?
なに？ 関口も朝練するの？
Sekiguchi, are you going to do morning practice, too?
Um...
えっと
Well...
えっと えーと
Um...
はい
Yes.
（大工）え？ マジで？
Seriously?
（みお）もう ２人のお昼まで
私が買うことになるとは
Nichijou 111
To think that I'll have to pay for both of your lunches...
Sorry!
ごめん
Well, since you don't have your wallets, it can't be helped.
まあ 財布ないんじゃ
しょうがないよね
よっ さすが みおちゃん 太っ腹
Of course Mio-chan understands!
So generous!
うっ ゴホッ ゴホッ
だ… 大丈夫？
Are you okay?
Geez.
もう ゆっこ 強くたたきすぎ
Yukko, you hit me too hard.
Sorry.
ごめん ごめん
おっとっと
Sorry, Mai-chan.
あっ 麻衣ちゃん ごめん
大丈夫
I'm fine.
Oh yeah, Yukko.
あっ そういや ゆっこ
Did you ask Nano-chan if we could come over today?
なのちゃんに
今日 行っていい？ って聞いた？
Crap!
（祐子）わっ すっかり忘れてた
（みお）ああ
I completely forgot!
ハアッ
All right!
よし！ じゃあちょっと
誕生日するって言ってくる
I'll tell her about the birthday party.
No, you can't!
それじゃダメだって
Just ask her if we can come over!
今日 行っていい？
だけでいいんだよ
I understand!
分かってるって
ううーん 分かってないって
No, you don't!
Geez.
もう 私が行く
I'll go myself!
I told you I'll go!
（祐子）私が行くって
（みお）あああ
No, I'll go!
いや 私が行く
I'll go!
（祐子）私が行くよ
（みお）私が！
I will...
（みお）ああ！ ハア
I'll go.
（麻衣）いってきます
Wait... Mai-chan, Mai-chan!
ちょ 麻衣ちゃん　麻衣ちゃん
モーメン プリー！
Moment, please!
Just a moment, please!
ジャス モーメン プリー！
…っと ハア
Well, I'm going to see Nano-chan now.
んじゃあ ちょっと
なのちゃん所 行ってくる
I must hurry!
善は急げ
（祐子）ハア ハア ハア
（笹原幸治郎(こうじろう)）んっ
（祐子）あたっ
I'm sorry!
わっ！ す… すみません
Don't worry about it.
（笹原）気にするな
（祐子）ああ
Go forth!
ゆけ！
I'm truly sorry!
（祐子）
ホントにすみませんでした
I'm sorry...
すみませんでした わちゃあ
（立花(たちばな)みさと）
なっ ブラックコーヒー
押しちゃった
I accidentally pressed black coffee.
（祐子）す… すみません！
I'm sorry!
Don't worry.
いいよ　いいよ
私のほうこそ ごめんね
It's partly my fault, too.
I'm sorry...
（祐子）
すみませんでした うへえ
If it says "Winner"
you get one more!!
Winner
（足音）
（桜井(さくらい)先生）あっ
ハア ハア ハア
あっ！ あ… 相生さん
廊下は静かに
A-Aioi-san,
please be quiet in the halls!
な… な… ナブシッ
Rainbow...
（ナレーター）虹
（祐子）ブシュッ
（桜井）ああ
ハア ハア　うわっ！
I found it!
（小木(おぎ)）おおっ あった
（中村(なかむら)先生）ハア ハア
いってててて
Ouch...
Aioi-san!
（なの）相生さん
（祐子）あ？
Are you all right?
大丈夫ですか？
おお！ なのちゃん
捜してたんだよ
Nano-chan!
I was looking for you!
Oh, really?
（なの）
えっ？ そうなんですか？
（祐子）うん　実は…
Yeah!
Actually...
ああっ いや これは…
That's, uh...
（祐子）ちょ 大丈夫？
痛くなかった？
Are you okay?
Didn't it hurt?
（なの）
あっ はい　大丈夫です
Yeah, I'm fine.
I see.
そっか　よかった
Thank goodness.
あっ といいますか
これは違くてですね
Anyway, this isn't what it looks like.
なんといいますか
How should I explain this?
（祐子）
ねえねえ そんなことより
今日 なのちゃん家(ち) 行っていい？
That's great and all, but is it all right if I come over today?
えっ？ あっ はい
Y-Yeah.
あっ そうだ！ あっ
That's righ-
That's a surprise, so I can't tell you.
それは サプライズなので
言えません
Eh? Uh...
（なの）え？ あの…
Well, see you later!
（祐子）
じゃあ またあとでね  ウフフ
O-Okay.
あっ はい
Well, I guess I'll have to buy some for Aioi-san, too.
じゃあ 相生さんたちの分も
買っておこうかな
（中村）ハア ハア ハア
First comes rock,
（はかせ･阪本･なの）
♪ 最初はグー その次パー
next comes paper.
Rockscispaper doesn't count,
rock, paper, scissors!
What the heck?
（はかせ･阪本）どゆこと？
ハア ハア ハア ハア
Nichijou 112
（祐子）ハア ハア ハア ハア
ハア
ハア ハア
ハア ハア ハア ハア
ハア
ハア ハア
（みお･祐子）
ハア ハア ハア ハア
This pumpkin!
このカボチャ　固(かて)え！
It's rock-hard!
O        ni    gi        ri
（阪本）ハアッ
Geez.
…ったくガキは
なんで ああ いつもいつも
Why does the kid always-
Taisho!
（中村）大将(たいしょう)？
（阪本）お？
Is that you, Taisho?
（中村）大将なのか？
（阪本）うん？
おっ　大将！
Taisho!
Nakamura!
（阪本）な… 中村！
I've been looking for you, Taisho!
捜してたんだぞ 大将
無事でよか…
Thank god you're saf-
なんで逃げるんだ
私を忘れたのか？
Why are you running away?
Have you forgotten me?
I'm running away because I haven't forgotten!
（阪本）
忘れてねえから 逃げるんだよ
（阪本）ミャウ
（中村）大将　ごはんだよ
Taisho, time for food.
（中村）はい
（阪本）ミー
Here.
（阪本）ミャウ ミャ
（中村）ん？
What's wrong, Taisho?
どうした 大将
食べないのか？
You're not going to eat?
（阪本）ミャーッ
（中村）おっ！ どうした？ 大将
（阪本）ミャ ミャ ミャ
What's wrong, Taisho?
It's time for a bath.
（中村）さあ お風呂だよ
（阪本）ニャア
よいしょ
（阪本）ミニャーッ
（中村）大将
Taisho!
Robotic Studies
Raising Cats
Damn.
（中村）しまった
急がないと遅刻だ
If I don't hurry, I'll be late.
Well, Taisho, I'm off.
大将　それじゃあ 行ってくる
おっ！ っとっとっと
しまった
Damn.
（阪本）ニャア
ニャア？
（阪本）ハア ハア ハア
Taisho!
大将
Come out, Taisho!
出てきて大将
Taisho!
大将
Hurry up and go, please!
（阪本）早く行ってくれえ
Oh, Nakamura-sensei?
（なの）あれ？ 中村先生？
（阪本）おっ？
Hello!
（なの）こんにちは
（中村）東雲！
Shinonome!
（阪本）
おおっ 娘　なんとかしろ
Girl, do something!
Is there something wrong?
どうしたんですか？
何か捜して…
Are you looking for something?
So this is what they mean by "like a robot to the flame."
（中村）飛んで火に入る
夏のロボとはこのことだ
Then again, I can talk to Shinonome any time at school.
…が しかし 東雲とは
学校で いつでも会える
Right now, Taisho is the priority.
ここは 大将優先だ
Sorry, Shinonome, have you seen a black cat?
すまん 東雲
黒猫を見なかったか？
You have a black cat, too?
えっ？ 中村先生のおうち
黒猫さん いるんですか？
ま… まあな
ちょっと逃げてしまってな
Well, kinda.
It escaped from me.
We have a black cat, too.
（なの）私の家にも
黒猫さん いるんですよ
I see.
そうか
Do you mind if I help you find it?
（なの）
私も一緒に捜していいですか？
お… おお　悪いな 東雲
Sure, sorry for the hassle, Shinonome.
No problem.
（なの）いえ
Are you stupid?!
（阪本）アホか お前は！
Oh, that's right, Nakamura-sensei.
あっ そうだ 中村先生
Could you tell me the name of your cat?
先生の猫さんの名前
何ていうんですか？
It's Taisho.
“大将”だ
ウフフフッ
面白い名前ですね
What an interesting name.
The cat at our house is Sakamoto-san.
私の家の猫さんは
“阪本さん”っていうんですよ
That's a strange name.
おかしな名前だな
I know.
ホント おかしな名前ですよね
ウフフフッ
Isn't it such a strange name?
Is he cute?
（なの）カワイイですか？
（中村）あ？
Is Taisho cute?
（なの）大将 カワイイですか？
（中村）あっ
な… 何を言ってるんだ お前は
What are you talking about?
You...
Well, it's not like Nakamura had bad intentions.
（阪本）まっ 中村も悪気があって
やったわけじゃねえしなあ
Then again...
しかし ああ ヘマばかりされたら
身がもたん
If that kind of crap starts again, my body won't hold.
Memories of
Nakamura's
Mess-ups
Memories of
Nakamura's
Mess-ups
Memories of
Nakamura's
Mess-ups
Memories of
Nakamura's
Mess-ups
Memories of
Nakamura's
Mess-ups
Memories of
Nakamura's
Mess-ups
Memories of
Nakamura's
Mess-ups
Memories of
Nakamura's
Mess-ups
Memories of
Nakamura's
Mess-ups
Memories of
Nakamura's
Mess-ups
Memories of
Nakamura's
Mess-ups
Memories of
Nakamura's
Mess-ups
Memories of
Nakamura's
Mess-ups
Memories of
Nakamura's
Mess-ups
Memories of
Nakamura's
Mess-ups
Memories of
Nakamura's
Mess-ups
Memories of
Nakamura's
Mess-ups
Wait. Hold on...
いや 待て待て
今も大して変わんなくねえか？
Memories of
the Kids'
Pranks
Memories of
the Kids'
Pranks
Memories of
the Kids'
Pranks
Memories of
the Kids'
Pranks
Memories of
the Kids'
Pranks
Memories of
the Kids'
Pranks
It hasn't changed that much now, either...
Memories of
the Kids'
Pranks
Memories of
the Kids'
Pranks
Memories of
the Kids'
Pranks
Memories of
the Kids'
Pranks
Memories of
the Kids'
Pranks
Memories of
the Kids'
Pranks
Memories of
the Kids'
Pranks
Memories of
the Kids'
Pranks
Memories of
the Kids'
Pranks
Memories of
the Kids'
Pranks
Memories of
the Kids'
Pranks
The scales aren't even tipping!
てんびんが　微動だにしねえ
Oh, look at the time.
（なの）
あっ もう こんな時間
すみません　中村先生
Sorry, Nakamura-sensei, but if I don't go home soon,
そろそろ私 帰らないと鮮度が
my food will...
（中村）あっ！ ああ そうか
I see.
If you find him, could I come see him?
見つかったら
大将 見にいっていいですか？
あっ おお 来い
いつでも来い あした来い！
Yes, come!
Come any time!
Come tomorrow!
（なの）フフッ
じゃあ 失礼します
Well, I'm heading off now.
Okay!
（中村）おう！
ウッフッフッ
フッフッフッハッハッ
Damn it!
（阪本）クソーッ
Either way, I'm screwed!
どっちにいっても
最悪じゃねえか
Nichijou 113
Professor, Sakamoto, I'm back!
（なの）
はかせ　阪本さん
ただいま
Nano!
（はかせ）なの
（はかせ）小っちゃいやつ
The small thing!
あっ あああっ！
出来たんですか？ はかせ
Professor, you made it?!
Sakamoto stepped on it again.
阪本に また踏まれました
（なの）どーん！
Sakamoto-san...
阪本さん
（はかせ）すっぽん！
（なの）え？ あれ？
いいんですか？ 取っちゃって
Is it okay for you to take it off again?
I'll make another one right now.
また すぐ作ります
Professor!
はかせっ
But it came off so easily.
でも こんなに 簡単に
取れたんですね
When I tried to take it off, it wouldn't budge!
自分で取ろうとしても
全然取れなかったのに
Well, that's because Nano can't take it off, but other people can!
それはね―
なのは自分で取れないけど
ほかの人は取れちゃうんだけど
I see...
（なの）なるほど
But even you can put it back in!
でもね 入れるのは
なのでも入れれるけど
（なの）なんて機能なんだ
What kind of feature is that?
あっ ところではかせ
By the way, Professor,
what kind of features does the small one have?
その“小っちゃいやつ”って
どんな機能なんですか？
If I make this, your thumb won't come off any more.
これ取ったら
親指 飛ばなくなっちゃうんだった
Yeah, I remember that feature...
（なの）
あったなあ そんな機能
（玄関チャイム）
（なの）あっ 相生さんたちかな？
I wonder if that's Aioi-san and her friends.
ええ！ ゆっこ？
わーい ゆっこだ
Yukko?
It's Yukko!
（なの）ウフッ
Oh, right. I need to put this key away.
あっ そうだ
ネジしまっとかなきゃ
I'll finally look like a normal person.
（なの）これで私も
普通の人みたいに見えるんだ
I wonder if I'll get along better with everyone now.
今までより
みんなと仲良くできるかな？
Going out with friends...
みんなと どこか
遊びに行ったり―
and enjoying things more normally...
もっと普通で 楽しい
日常が待ってるかも
That kind of daily life is waiting for me!
（祐子）
ねえねえ そんなことより
今日 なのちゃん家(ち) 行っていい？
That's great and all, but is it all right if I come over today?
That's because it's cute!
なぜなら カワイイからです
（祐子）
なのちゃんは なのちゃんだし
それでいいんじゃない？
You're Nano-chan.
Isn't that enough?
I came over to say that.
今日は それを
言いに来たのだった
I'd forgotten.
忘れてたよ
Nano-chan!
なーのちゃん
Nano!
なの
Girl.
（阪本）娘っ
Be quiet!
（祐子）シーッ 静かに
大事なところなんだから
This is the important part.
I got it.
（みお）分かった 分かった
（みお･祐子･麻衣）せーのっ
Nano-chan!
なーのちゃん！
（祐子）フフーン
ジャーン
誕生日おめでとう
Happy birthday!
I brought some cake over.
ケーキ買ってきたよ
Oh, Aioi-san!
（なの）あ… 相生さん
誕生日って
えっ？ どうして？
Birthday... How did you...?
It's because it's a surprise!
サプライズですよ
サプライズ
（はかせ）ケーキ！
It's cake!
Cake, cake, cake!
（祐子）ああっ
（はかせ）ケーキ食べる ケーキ
Geez, Professor.
待って はかせ
グイグイきすぎ
Oh, Professor!
（ケーキの箱をたたく音）
（なの）あっ ちょっとはかせ
Come on, Professor.
ほらほら はかせ
（はかせ･祐子･みお）どーんっ！
Look what happened!
（祐子）なんてこった
（はかせ）ケーキが
The cake...
（祐子）どどど… どうしよう
えーと えーと
What should we do...?
I have one more...
こっちに もう１つ
Mai-chan!
（みお･祐子）麻衣ちゃん
What is that?!
（みお･祐子）どゆこと？
Yeah!
やった！
（はかせ）
ねえ もう１回やろ もう１回
But I wonder how everyone knew...
けど どうして みんな
知ってたんだろう
...that today was my birthday.
私の誕生日
Nano's
Birthday
Nano!
（はかせ）なの
（なの）うっ
I made the small thing!
（はかせ）
小っちゃいやつ 作ってきた！
Professor.
はかせ
This key has been a bother to me,
確かに このネジがあって
不便だったし―
and I really wanted to take it off,
ものすごーく
取りたかったんですけど
そのっ
but I want to stay like this!
（はかせ）すっぽん！ ぽん
（なの）私…
（なの）このままがいいです！
（はかせ）ぽん！
What this small thing does is: when Nano is happy,
この小っちゃいのはね―
なのが うれしくなっちゃった
ときに―
it turns the key a little.
ネジがそこそこ回る
小っちゃいやつなのです
What is that supposed to be?
（なの）何ですか それは！
エヘヘ
あっ そうだ
Oh, right!
Professor, can you take this cake over there?
はかせ このケーキ
持っていってもらっていいですか？
わあっ またケーキだ
It's another cake!
I'll be taking the tea over.
私 お茶 持っていきますので
Roger that!
分かった
Cake, cake, cake, cake...
ケーキ ケーキ ケーキ
ケーキ  わっ！
はかせ？
Professor!
Cake...
（祐子･はかせ）ケーキ
Geez. What are you two doing?
もう 何やってんの２人とも
（なの）
あっ 相生さん　大丈夫ですか？
Aioi-san, are you all right?
Nano-chan, get something to clean this up!
（祐子）
なのちゃん　拭く物 拭く物
（なの）あっ はいっ
Yes!
Here's the candle.
（麻衣）ここにロウソク
I want to do it, too!
（はかせ）
ずるい はかせもやる
Mai-chan, we need to do something about this first...
麻衣ちゃん　それより
何というか整えないと
Something to clean... something to clean...
（なの）拭く物 拭く物
プッ アッハッハッハッ
ウッフッフッフッフッ
Mai-chan!
（みお）麻衣ちゃん
（なの）
えーと えーと えーと ああっ
Here's another one.
（麻衣）もう１本
（みお）いや だから整えないと
As I said, something else!
Mai-chan, stop, stop!
（みお）ああ　麻衣ちゃん
ストップ ストップ
（なの）あのっ えーと えーと
（はかせ）何だこれ 何だこれ
Motivation
ヘプシッ
What's wrong, Mio-chan?
どうしたの？ みおちゃん
I can't stop sneezing...
なかなか くしゃみが止まんなくて
What are you talking about?
何言ってんの？
You can stop sneezing with willpower!
くしゃみなんて
気合いで止まるもんだよ
So until I gather enough willpower,
じゃあ 気合い入れるまでの
くしゃみを止めるには―
what should I do about the sneezing?
どうしたらいいの？
You just have to stop it!
とにかく 止めるっきゃない！
It's impossible.
無理 無理
There's a simple idiot here.